Guide to the Hal and Barbara Dodge Borland Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- II. April 1991 Acquisition, 1904-1990; 5.25; (7 boxes)
  - "Witches Laughter," drafts, holograph and typescript and printed material, undated (Box 52)
  - The Greater Hunger, contract and copyright documents, circa 1960 (Box 52)
  - Osborn, Robert, correspondence and printed material, 1964 (Box 52)
  - Newspaper clipping, circa 1988 (Box 52)
  - The Greater Hunger, "Hetty," third copy, typescript, 1988 (Box 52)
  - The Orange Anthology of Poetry, circa 1926 (Box 52)
  - Audubon Magazine, 1970s-1990s; 2 (Box 52)
  - Various magazines, undated (Box 52)
  - Excerpts from Twelve Moons of the Year published in Science Digest and Reader's Digest, 1980; 3 (Box 61)
  - Excerpts of Hal Borland's writings published in Reader's Digest, 1955-1959; 3 (Box 61)
  - Audio cassettes in cases, 1957-1971, undated; 4; 22 audio cassettes (Box 52)
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    Cassettes contain the following labels:
    Case 1: "Pat Barking," "Bird Songs followed by H & B collaborating on novel," "Hal Borland - interview re: When the Legends Die, 12-28-71," "WOR Interview Beyond Your Doorstep ," "Cleveland Interview - Country Editor's Boy - Eugenia ," "Bird Songs," "TV Interview - WNYC Oct 25, 1967 - Hill Country Harvest ," "Albany Interview," "Cleveland Interview - Lake Erie Science Lecture."
    Case 2: "HB & BDB working on story - dialogue," "HB & BDB working on story material," "G Fox Authors - The Dog Who Came to Stay ," "Two good recordings of September Song," "Army Hour, Cab Calloway reading Creed by Hal Borland," "Army Hour, HB Midwest read by Richard Kiley," "The Quiet," "Army Hour - HB's 'The South' from America is Americans ," "September Song 1961."
    Case 3: "Strange Music," "Widow," "First Side," "Sonnyboy," "Christmas Notes."
    Case 4: "Thoreau Society - HB Speech, Part I, 7/13/68," "Thoreau Society - Dr. Reginald Cook's address," "Thoreau Society - HB Address, Part II, 7/13/68," "CEVAL 9 70," "WQXR Interview - This Hill, This Valley, 1957," "HB Dictating," "BDB Birthday."
  - "I Belong to You," holograph draft and audio cassette, undated (Box 52)
  - "Love Dream," "I Belong to You," and "Love Fiction" audio cassettes, undated; 2; 4 audio cassettes (Box 52)
  - "Time Out to Live, Hal Boslandia, 10/26/53," WHOO AM-FM (phonographic record), 1953 October 26
- Oversize, 1.5; (6 boxes)
  - New York World's Fair clippings (1965 and 1981 Acquisitions), 1939-1940 (Box 53)
  - Book of Days, proof (1965 and 1981 Acquisitions), 1976 (Box 53)
  - A Countryman's Flowers, repro proofs (1965 and 1981 Acquisitions), circa 1981 (Box 53)
  - Sundial of the Seasons, text and illustration layouts (1965 and 1981 Acquisitions), circa 1955 (Box 54)
  - A Countryman's Flowers, layout (1965 and 1981 Acquisitions), circa 1981 (Box 55)
  - "Non-Fiction Articles, H.B., 1937---," scrapbook with articles and correspondence (1965 and 1981 Acquisitions), 1932-1962 (Box 56)
  - The Dog Who Came to Stay, five-part serialization in Dutch magazine De Spiegel, printed version (1965 and 1981 Acquisitions) (Box 57)
  - Holiday magazines with writings of Hal Borland (1965 and 1981 Acquisitions), 1978-1979; 2 (Box 57)
  - Boy's Life and American Education magazines with writings of Hal Borland (1965 and 1981 Acquisitions), 1966, 1985 (Box 57)
  - Newspapers with writings of Hal Borland (1965 and 1981 Acquisitions), 1970s (Box 57)
  - Russian magazine containing "Life" by Hal Borland (1965 and 1981 Acquisitions), 1976 (Box 57)
  - Magazines and tear sheets (April 1991 Acquisition), 1950s; 3 (Box 58)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.21; (1 box) + 1 portfolio
  - The Quiet Comes, tape recording of Hal Borland editorial, 1975 (Box 59)
  - "Time Out to Live, Hal Boslandia, 10/26/53," WHOO AM-FM (phonographic record), 1953 October 26 (Box Port 60)